本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： vernie 卢尔摩斯 魔法莉露姆 许块块
校对： 许块块   后期： 泡面君
还以为我们会去索伦托度蜜月
Thought we might go to Sorrento for the honeymoon.
在这儿钓鱼也不错 不是吗
Good fishing there, is it?
哈哈 你钓到一条! 卷上来 卷上来
Ha-hey, you got one! Reel her in, reel her in.
- 哇...拉上来 - 鱼竿都要断了
- Wha... There you go. - It's gonna break!
这是什么
What is it?
- 转过去 - 休斯...
- Turn your back. - Hugh...
- 那是...- 多蒂 我叫你转过身去!
- That's... - Dottie, I said turn your back!
费雪小姐探案集 第二季第十二集
不自然之习惯
没有失踪人口记录 先生
Nothing in the missing persons record, sir.
打扰一下 先生们 多蒂叫我载她来这儿
Pardon us, gentlemen. Dot asked me to drive her here.
多蒂 我叫你别来这儿
Dot, I told you not to come.
她是天主教徒 休斯
She's Catholic, Hugh.
是天主教的肩布 先生
It's the scapular, sir.
我不希望她看到 但是...
I don't want her to see it, but...
我想帮忙
I want to help.
多蒂可能知道哪个学校或教区有上面的箴言
Dot may know which school or parish favours whatever motto's on it.
好吧
Alright.
穿着这件肩布死去的人
'Whoever dies wearing this scapular
可以免受永恒之火的痛苦
shall not suffer eternal fire.'
那背面呢
And the back?
救赎的标记 卡梅尔峰的圣母玛利亚
'Behold the sign of salvation.' Our Lady of Mount Carmel.
这说明不了什么 任何人都可能有那个
That's no help. Anybody could have that one.
这看起来像绳子烧伤的
These look like rope burns.
柯林斯发现她的时候 她被捆着
She was bound when Collins found her.
还有其他东西
There's something else.
这被缝在她的衬衫上
It was stitched into her smock.
名字被洗掉了 但是... 有一个宗教徽章
The name's been washed off, but... there's a religious emblem.
那是妓女收容所的洗衣标记
That's the Magdalene laundry mark,
是圣奇迹姐妹修道院的
from the Convent of the Sisters of the Holy Miracle.
- 你确定吗 - 是的
- Are you sure? Yes.
那些堕落的无依无靠的姑娘为我们洗衣服
The fallen and friendless girls do our laundry.
阿流苏斯修女 我是罗宾森警探
Mother Aloysius. Inspector Robinson.
我想 主教已告知你我的来访
The... Bishop has cleared my visit with you, I take it.
他没说你会带一个同伴来
He didn't say anything about you bringing a companion.
尊敬的芬乐妮·费雪小姐
The Honourable Miss Phryne Fisher.
费雪小姐是一个女侦探
Miss Fisher is a lady detective.
是啊 不幸的是
Yes. Well, unfortunately,
南城警方还没有任用女警
City South Police have yet to appoint any policewomen.
谢天谢地 我很高兴能这样工作
Thankfully, I'm happy to serve that function.
那样的话 我想主教就会同意了
In that case, I'm sure the Bishop will approve.
女警
Policewoman?
别担心 杰克 我永远不会穿上警服的
Don't worry, Jack. You'll never get me in that uniform.
当然 除非你逼我
Unless, of course, you cuff me.
修女! 修女 我们确认过了
Mother! Mother, we've confirmed.
凯瑟琳要去给一个卖女帽的当学徒
Catherine is to be apprenticed to a milliner.
什么...现在...
Oh! What... now...
如果你的针线活和我想得一样好
If your needlepoint is anywhere near as good as I think it is,
你一定会很成功的
you're going to be a great success.
去门口等吧 凯瑟琳 出租车一会儿就到
Wait by the gate, Catherine. The cab will arrive presently.
警察是来调查伯纳黛特失踪的事的
The police are here about Bernadette's disappearance.
波普塔 是监督姑娘们的项目的
Perpetua, who oversees all our programs with the girls.
这是多米尼加修女
And Sister Dominica.
我们没洗过你的衣服吗
Don't we do your laundry?
洗过 事实上
You do, indeed.
洗得非常好
To absolute perfection.
你们知道伯纳黛特的全名吗
Do you know Bernadette's full name?
不知道
I'm afraid we don't.
几年前她来找我们的时候是个孤儿
She came to us as an orphan some years ago now,
我们以圣灵的名义给她取名
and we named her for the saint.
- 你说她失踪了 - 是的
- You said she's gone missing. - Yes.
不久前她被安排在联邦酒店工作
She was placed in employment at the Federal Hotel some time ago,
但是昨晚她回来了 精神不太正常
but she returned to us late last night in a state.
为什么呢
About what?
她觉得做厨房帮工有失了她的身份
She was of the opinion hotel kitchen hand was beneath her.
非常激动 我无法安抚她 就哄她睡觉
Hysterical. I couldn't calm her. I put her to bed.
但是早上她就走了 再一次
But by morning she was gone. Again.
你们有谁见过这个吗
Are any of you familiar with this?
我们怀疑这可能是伯纳黛特的
We suspect it could be Bernadette's.
我们今天早晨从河里捞到了她的尸体
I'm afraid we fished her body out of the river this morning.
看起来她的死并不是意外
And it appears her death wasn't an accident.
我的上帝!
Oh... dear God!
我会带你们去洗衣房
I'll take you through the laundry.
那晚我就让她待在这里
This is where I put her for the night.
为什么不是宿舍
Not in the dormitory?
都过了十二点了 她可能会吵醒别的姑娘的
It was past midnight. She would've unsettled the other girls.
我们叫它忏悔室
We call it the Penitence Room.
可以回去工作了 去接安格斯轧布机的活
Back to work now. You'll take over from Agnes on the mangle.
我最爱的工作
My favourite job.
记得乞求主原谅你
And remember to beg our Lord's forgiveness
这恶劣又不知好歹的态度
for your wicked, ungrateful attitude.
我那样做 你觉得他会付我们薪水吗
If I do that, do you think he'll start paying us wages?
艾达 快去
Ada, go.
我叫玛丽
My name is Mary.
你连亲圣母玛利亚的脚都不配
You ain't fit to kiss the Holy Mother's feet,
更别说和她同名了
let alone share her name.
你是说这些女孩都是没有薪水的吗
Do you mean to tell me these girls aren't paid?
我们蒙受神的祝福住在主的房子里 费雪小姐
We're blessed to live in the Lord's house, Miss Fisher.
这里没有人拿薪水的
No-one gets paid here.
妓女收容所洗衣房是不受劳动法约束的
The Magdalene Laundries are exempt from usual labour laws.
你能让这地方再悲惨一点吗
Do you think you could make it any less harrowing?
这里简直是大卫科波菲尔里的场景
This place is straight out of the pages of David Copperfield.
伯纳黛特是怎么出去的
How did Bernadette get out of here?
- 那些从窗户上挂下来 - 另一边是什么
- Those were hanging from the window. - What's on the other side?
正巧是河岸 非常凑巧
The riverbank, as it happens. It's quite a drop.
可能她不小心滑入河中
Perhaps she slipped and fell.
我要和姑娘们一个一个单独聊聊
I'll need to talk to the girls one by one.
当然
Of course.
但是... 你的女警最好在外面等
Though... we'd prefer your policewoman wait outside.
我更希望她在场
I would prefer her presence.
姑娘们很感激我们提供的庇护所 警探
The girls are grateful for the shelter we provide, Inspector.
我们不想因为聊到工人的权利
We don't want to stir up dissatisfaction
和规则而引发她们的不满
with the talk of workers' rights and regulations.
我确定你们不想
I'm sure you don't.
我们这儿不是一个工厂 我们是一个大家庭
We're not a factory here. We're a family.
那如果费雪小姐不发表她的意见的话...
If Miss Fisher keeps her opinions to herself...
没关系 杰克 比起干这个我更愿意走
It's alright, Jack. I'd rather leave than do that.
我还有其他线索要调查 还要找个新的洗衣工
I do have other leads to follow. And a new launderer to find.
看...好了
And... voila.
这些床单之间系的是平结
These sheets were tied with thief knots.
根本无法承受一个年轻姑娘的重量
They'd never bear the weight of a young girl.
我确实知道怎么打结 费雪小姐
Hm. I do know my knots, Miss Fisher.
我很好奇你是怎么知道的
I'm curious as to how you do.
我以前认识一个葡萄牙海员
There was this Portuguese sailor I once knew.
别...说了
Don't... Enough.
所以是有人准备了绳子来掩饰伯纳黛特的逃跑
So somebody prepared the rope to explain Bernadette's escape.
谁会那么做呢
Who would need to do that?
那个放她走的人 姑娘们中的一个
Whoever let her out. One of the girls?
她们不会来了
They're hardly forthcoming.
你以为呢 她们生活在忏悔室的恐惧之下
Well, what do you expect? They live in fear of the Penitence Room.
我爸爸曾经把我锁在碗柜里
My father used to lock me in a cupboard to
试图摧毁我的意志
try and break my spirit.
显然关得不够久啊 那波普塔呢
Clearly didn't leave you there long enough. What about Perpetua?
或者是修女中的一个
Or one of the nuns.
我无法想象她们会帮伯纳黛特
I can't imagine them doing Bernadette a favour.
- 你...折了它 - 过来
- Oh, you've... you've creased it now. - Oh, come here.
杰克 费雪小姐
Jack. Miss Fisher.
你们俩这些天走得很近啊
You do indeed keep close company these days.
我正要走
I was just on my way out.
我接到一个麻烦的电话 主教非常生气
I received a disturbing telephone call from a very irate bishop.
和天主教会相处我们得非常小心 杰克
We need to tread very carefully with the Catholic Church, Jack.
你知道的
You know that.
似乎太过小心了吧
A little too carefully, it seems.
如果那个洗衣房不是开在修道院
If that laundry was run outside of the convent,
它就违反了儿童保护法
it would be in breach of child cruelty laws.
教会对更高的法律负责 我们必须得尊重它
The Church answers to a higher law, and we're obliged to respect that.
这就是为什么你要把这个案子
Which is why you're handing the investigation
交接给警探欧·谢贺尼斯去调查
over to Detective Inspector O'Shaughnessy.
欧·谢贺尼斯没这个能力
O'Shaughnessy is an incompetent!
欧·谢贺尼斯也许没你有能力 杰克
O'Shaughnessy may not be up to your standards, Jack.
但是他是天主教徒 这是很好的优势
But he has the distinct advantage of being Catholic.
这现在是他的案子了 行政长官的指令
It is now his case, by order of the Chief Commissioner.
那好吧 我...我要跟他谈谈
Well, then I... I... I need to speak with him.
行政长官豪尔今天早晨辞职了
Chief Commissioner Hall resigned this morning.
那谁来代替他呢
Well, who's his replacement?
- 你正看着他呢 - 恭喜你
- You're looking at him. Congratulations.
今天是我上任的第一天 别跟我添难处
It's my first day on the job. Don't make it any more difficult.
乔治·桑德森真的相信一个
Does George Sanderson really believe that a man
名字前有欧的男人
with an O in front of his name
会控告一群修女吗
will bring charges against a pack of nuns?
别管了 费雪小姐
Leave it alone, Miss Fisher.
我们这么辛苦为那些修女找工作
We worked so hard to find jobs for those convent girls.
那些心怀感激的姑娘
The Gratitude girls were not the ones
不是我们从泥潭里救出来的
we plucked out from the gutter.
只有最规矩的会被选中
Only the best behaved were chosen.
什么 那剩下的注定成为奴隶
What, and the rest were doomed to slavery
待在那满是肥皂沫的可怕的洗衣房里
amongst the suds of that hideous laundry?
坏姑娘 好床单 拿不到一分钱
Bad girls, good sheets and not a penny in wages.
如果我没遇到你 就会去修道院 小姐
I would've turned to the convent if I hadn't met you, Miss.
她们没有选择
They have no choice.
更正当的理由不去剥削她们
All the more reason not to exploit them.
为了你的好姑娘们 普顿斯阿姨
As for your 'good' girls, Aunt Prudence,
你要告诉我有两个女孩失踪了吗
are you telling me that two of them have gone missing?
乔安不是失踪 她逃跑了
Joan did not go missing, she absconded.
在我感谢赞助人的晚宴上 她甚至不在安排中
During my Gratitude Patrons dinner. She wasn't even part of the program.
但是我给了她一个机会
But I gave her a chance,
在我家一个不错的职位
a plum placement in my very own household.
伯纳黛特也有一个不错的职位 在联邦酒店
Bernadette had a plum placement too, at the Federal Hotel.
我们的董事都有不错的人脉
Oh, all of our board are well connected.
沃思顿家家族 康普顿家家族 弗莱彻家家族
The Worthingtons, the Comptons, the Fletchers,
我们尽其所能
and we all do what we can.
弗莱彻是悉尼的弗莱彻吗
Fletcher as in Sidney Fletcher?
是的 最年长的那个
Yes, their eldest.
他是乔治·桑德森的教子 警察局副局长
He's godson of George Sanderson, deputy police commissioner.
杰克前妻萝丝的未婚夫
And fiance to Jack's ex-wife, Rosie.
你很善于用迂回的方式看待事情 亲爱的
You have a very roundabout way of looking at things, dear.
是的
Ah. Yes.
这就是乔安
There's Joan.
乔安 她看起来不像是会逃跑的人
Joan? She didn't seem the runaway type.
她做的麦片粥很棒
She made a wonderful flummery.
连那些带瓶塞的玻璃杯
Not even those bottle-top glasses
也无法拯救我的皇家阿尔伯特茶具
could save my Royal Albert tea set from ruin.
早上好 修女
Morning, Sister.
荣耀的费雪小姐洗衣房 一如既往
The Honourable Miss Fisher's laundry, as per usual.
今天都星期三了 一如既往 应该是周一
Today's Wednesday. As per usual, it's Monday.
八套段子床单 十八套内衣裤
8 sets of satin sheets, 18 pairs of smalls,
十二件女士背心
12 camisoles?
- 有客人留宿  - 是那个女人
- House guests. - That woman!
- 搬到后面去 - 主保佑你 修女
- Put it round the back. - Bless you, Sister.
不要太大声 他们在晨祷
Keep the noise down. They're at morning prayers.
没人
All clear.
做圣职本来是简单的选择
Taking holy orders would've been the easier option.
你们居然称之为开车
You call that driving?
如果你喜欢 我很乐意换辆车
Happy to swap cars if you like.
你准备怎么出去
How will you get out?
一个小时后 我们在前门见
Meet you out the front in an hour.
给我三个不应该在这大叫的理由
Give me three good reasons why I shouldn't scream the place down.
给我三个你应该大叫的理由
Give me three good reasons why you should.
为什么昨天波普塔叫你艾达?
Why did Perpetua call you Ada yesterday?
所有来这的人都得改名字 为了神圣
They change everybody's name when you get here, to saints.
为什么圣艾达这么出名
What was Saint Ada's claim to fame?
她是一个被献祭的处女
She was a dedicated virgin.
真是后无来者
Hard act to follow.
这是工厂领班的主意 不是我
This was the factory foreman's idea. Not mine.
你知道我并不是警察 玛丽
You know I'm not the police, Mary.
伯纳黛特回来的那晚 你见到她了么?
Did you see Bernadette the night she came back?
因为她的原因我才得以缓刑
I was reprieved on her account.
那是一个月以来我第一次住进宿舍
It was the first time in a month I got to sleep in the dorm.
她像个孩子一样哭闹
She was bawling like a baby
并且乞求波普塔不要让他找到她
and begging Perpetua not to let him get her.
谁?
Who?
她提到了一个外面旅店的男人
She said something about a man outside the hotel, um...
还总是说到一辆车 一辆昂贵的黑色小轿车
And she was going on about a car. A fancy black car.
- 她提到了乔安 - 乔安?
- And she was talking about Joan. - Joan?
我们叫她四眼 是修女的走狗
We called her Four Eyes. The nuns' pet.
她和伯纳黛特曾经是最好的朋友
She and Bernadette were best friends
直到他们不再让乔安工作
until they sent Joan off to work
而是被一个有钱的老悍妇看中了她做饭的才能
for some rich old battleaxe who took a shine to her cooking.
伯纳黛特是不是会间歇性的发狂?
Was Bernadette prone to hysterics?
我不太了解她
I hardly knew her.
他们让好女孩远离我们这些坏蛋
They kept the good girls away from us bad eggs.
但是她留下了信息
But she left a message.
我今天早上才在那看到
I only saw it there this morning.
'一一二 德·威赫'
'112 De Vere.'
-  这是划上去的 - 用这些
- This has been scratched in. - With these.
乔安的
Joan's.
早上好 柯林斯
Good morning, Collins.
长官 这是伯纳黛特的验尸报告
Sir, the... the autopsy report on Bernadette.
把它给 欧·谢贺尼斯 他现在负责这个案子
Um... Give it to O'Shaughnessy. He's in charge of this case now.
- 但是 但是  - 直接送去 柯林斯
- But... but... - Immediately, Collins.
我也送弗莱彻先生去欧·谢贺尼斯么 长官?
Shall I send Mr Fletcher to O'Shaughnessy too, sir?
你昨天给他打过电话 让他过来的
You telephoned him yesterday, asked him to come in.
- 他和您的妻子 您的前妻 前妻
- He and your wife... your ex-wife. Ex-wife.
是的 柯林斯
Y-yes, Collins.
我还得这样说多少次啊
How many times do I have to say that?
所以 你是为什么被关在那
So, why were you locked in there?
这次?
This time?
我把糖换成泻药放在了修女的木薯粉布丁里面
I put Epsom salts instead of sugar in the sisters' tapioca pudding.
她们整晚都在去厕所
They were up all night with the shits...
我向你保证 我会亲自重新指派这个案子
I assure you, I have personally reassigned the case.
情况不会再继续恶化了
There will be no more aggravation.
专员 波普塔 多么出色的风干方式 是吧?
Commissioner. Perpetua. Excellent drying weather, wouldn't you say?
- 你闯入了修道院 - 不 当然不是
- You broke into the convent. - No, of course not.
我是溜进去的
I was smuggled.
我以为这种轻浮的社会人会睡到中午
I thought these dilettante society types slept till noon.
非法入侵 打破并且侵占
Unlawful trespass, break and entry.
我希望这个女人能乖乖就范
I want this woman brought to heel.
你是不是想让我也洗衣服去?
Would you like me to roll over and fetch too?
你似乎对她有些动摇
You seem to have some sway over her.
萝丝 西德尼 你们怎么来了?
Rosie, Sidney, what are you doing here?
我们是被传唤的 至少西德尼是这样
We were summoned. Well, at least Sidney was.
我们过来看看能否帮帮那个可怜的修道院女孩
We've come to see if we can help with that poor convent girl.
作为感恩会的一名董事
And as a member of the Gratitude board.
我的阿姨告诉过我
So my aunt tells me.
我 忘记取消这次会面
I... forgot to cancel the appointment.
父亲 我知道你让杰克不再
Father, I believe you've taken
插手这个案子 为什么?
Jack off this case.Why?
这是外交问题 亲爱的 杰克明白
It's a diplomacy issue, my dear. Jack understands.
这不是你该担心的问题
It's nothing for you to worry about.
是的 是的 是的
No, no, no.
但是 如果你不把费雪跟的这么紧
But... if you don't keep Miss Fisher under a tighter rein,
你会发现你几乎停下了所有的工作
you may find yourself suspended from all duties.
再见 费雪小姐
Goodbye, Miss Fisher.
杰克 对不起
Jack, I'm sorry.
拜托告诉我你的非法入侵是值得付出这一切
Please tell me your break-in was worth all this... fuss.
你来判断吧
You tell me.
玛丽在忏悔屋里发现了这个
Mary found these in the Penitence Room
就在伯纳黛特失踪的第二天
the day after Bernadette did her disappearing act.
乔安的 普顿斯阿姨的那个发疯的女仆
Joan's. Aunt Prudence's runaway maid.
仅仅 根据玛丽所说
Only, according to Mary,
乔安是个好女孩 从来没有进过忏悔屋
Joan was a good girl and never did time in the Penitence Room.
那它是怎么到那的?
How'd they get there?
伯纳黛特回修道院的时候带在身上的
Bernadette had them with her when she returned to the convent,
然后她用这幅眼镜在墙上划出了这个
and she used the glass to scratch this into the wall.
- 一一二 德·威赫- 是个地址?
- 112 De Vere. - An address?
也许 是她提到的那个男人的地址
Possibly. Of the man she referred to.
为什么划在墙上? 为什么不告诉修女
Why scratch it into a wall? Why not tell the nuns?
根据玛丽所说 她试过 但是
Well, according to Mary, she tried.
也许她们没有听进去
But... perhaps they didn't listen.
柯林斯!
Collins!
我真的非常抱歉 杰克
I really am very sorry, Jack,
因为我 你这浑水趟的太深了
that you're in so much hot water because of me.
别这么悔恨 那会让我误解的
Don't be remorseful. It only confuses me.
柯林斯当我跟你说
Collins, when I told you
把验尸报告直接送走 我
to send on that autopsy report immediately, I...
我还没来得及处理这个 长官
Hardly had time to get on to it, sir.
谢谢你
Thank you.
毕竟它是寄给我的
It is addressed to me after all.
谢天谢地 我可不想把你想成不服从命令的人
Thank goodness. I'd hate to think you were disobeying a directive.
所以 被害者是先死亡的 还是溺水而死的
So, was the victim already dead or did she drown in the river, sir?
杰克?
Jack?
溺水而死的 柯林斯
Drowned, Collins.
休斯不可能因把她钓起来而高兴
Can't have been pleasant for Hugh to fish her out of the water.
溺水超过一夜 头发下面发现了伤口
'In the water overnight, injury found under the hair,
应该是被钝器所伤
most likely caused by a blunt instrument.'
- 但那并不致命 - 是的
- But not the cause of death. - No.
肺部有很多海水
There was sea water in the lungs,
值得注意的是成分分析表中
notable for an exceptionally
盐分的含量异常的高
high saline content.
然后尸体就无法从修道院顺流而下
Then the body can't have come downstream from the convent.
那应该是被上游海湾的水冲刷的
It must have been washed upstream from the bay!
还要更远
Much further than that.
肺部还有红藻的痕迹
The lungs also contain traces of red algae,
那是在亚拉河以及菲利普港湾都找不到的品种
a type that is not found in either the River Yarra or Port Phillip Bay.
这是休斯和多蒂发现女孩的地方
Here's where Hugh and Dottie found the girl.
暖河 为什么叫这个名字?
The Warmies? Why do they call it that?
因为那里的水是温暖的
Because the water's warm,
因为那里有一个发电站
on account of the power station here.
潮汐从这进出
Tide comes in, tide goes out.
只要海湾或者河流里有干扰物都会被抓住
Anything bobbing about in the bay or the river can get caught up.
那怎么解释伯纳黛特肺部的盐水呢?
How do you explain the salt water in Bernadette's lungs?
码头有许多外籍船只
Some foreign ship in dock
在离她喝酒的很近的地方倾倒压舱物
was dumping ballast near where she went into the drink?
是什么方法 让她在离开修道院以后
Somehow, after leaving the convent,
让她到达了码头
she winds up in the docks,
在那她被扔到海里喂鲨鱼 然后被冲回上游
where she's fed to the sharks and washes upriver.
- 你有没有什么想法? - 还没
- That make any sense to you? - Not yet.
- 如果我们知道船是从哪里来的 - 红海
- If we knew where the ship was from... - The Red Sea.
这里说了 那里的海水有异常高的含盐量
It says here, it has an exceptionally high salinity,
看上去是红色则是因为一种特殊的藻类
and the reason it looks red is because of some special algae.
我们能找到谁在港湾? 西西侄女的丈夫知道
Can we find out who's in port? Cec's niece's husband will know.
打扰一下 费雪小姐
Excuse me, Miss Fisher.
有一位年轻的女士想要见你
There's a young lady here demanding to see you.
- 你的开锁器 谢谢 这是个奖励
- Your lock pick. Thank you. It worked a treat.
你这样影响不好 费雪小姐
You're a bad influence, Miss Fisher.
而且你留不住她的
And, no, you can't keep her.
她叫玛丽 我已经确定不会送她回洗衣房
Her is Mary. And I certainly won't send her back to that laundry.
她明显不适合繁重的体力劳动
She is clearly unfit for heavy duties
我只想找份工作 什么工作都行
All I want is a job, any job.
但是谁会顾我这种情况的女孩
But who's going to take in a girl in my condition?
不行 绝对不行
No. Absolutely not.
但是你喜欢挑战 普顿斯 阿姨
But you love a challenge, Aunt Prudence.
你是那么的皮革马利翁
Your very own Pygmalion.
百香果子冻 我就知道
Passionfruit flummery, I should've known.
玛丽自己做的
Mary made it herself.
他们说仁爱始于家
They do say charity begins at home.
真要这样么 芬乐妮
Honestly, Phryne!
我位列十三名董事之中
I sit on 13 boards,
我大部分的生命都在花钱买有价值的东西
I spend most of my life raising money for worthy causes.
你不认为我已经做的够多了么?
Don't you think I do enough?
怎么了 波特?
What is it, Bert?
我们在港长的办公室遇到了障碍
We struck a snag at the harbourmaster's office.
西西侄子的丈夫再也不会给家人行方便
Cec's niece's husband doesn't do family favours anymore.
要想得到那艘船的名字得花点钱
Getting that ship's name is going to cost.
他在哪?
Where is he?
他十分的唠叨 老泰德 只要你能让他开口
He's a chatty one, old Ted. Once you loosen his tongue.
我想十磅足够让他开口了
Oh! Well, I think £10 has loosened it too much.
下次我要种喇叭花是 我会问问您的建议的
Next time I'm planting petunias, I'll ask your advice.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you, thank you.
抱歉 长官
Sorry, sir.
德·威赫·克里斯森特是香农的苗圃
De Vere Crescent is Shannon's Nursery.
他妈的
Damn!
- 也许是个名字 - 那数字又是什么?
- Maybe it's a name. - Then what are the numbers?
邮政信箱 登记号码?
Post office box, motor registration?
德·威赫听上去像是外国的
De Vere sounds foreign.
她是一个商用船叫做潘达斯
She's a merchant ship called the Pandarus,
往返于安特卫普和墨尔本通过红海
on a run between Antwerp and Melbourne via the Red Sea.
船长是比利时人 一个叫威廉姆·德·威赫的
Captain's Belgian. One William De Vere.
一一二
112!
昂贵的黑色轿车
A fancy black car.
看上去像是我们的船长
Looks like our captain.
泰德说她在那停了几周了
Ted says she docked three weeks ago,
可是她下一周就又要起航了
but she's due to sail out in another week.
运什么是的? 货单上写的是 白糖
What's she carrying? According to the manifest, sugar.
易于掩盖些不好的东西
Could be a cover for something dodgy.
那我们最好想个办法上船找找看
Then we better find a way to get on board and find out.
伙计
Mate!
没错 搁浅怎么样了?
Yeah, what about the bilge?
不要打开舱门
But keep that hatch  closed!
- 德·威赫船长 - 又怎么了?
- Captain De Vere. - What now?
- 又沉下去了 - 那就修好它
- down again. - Well, fix it.
拖延的已经够久了 我希望能重新赶上进度
There's been enough delays. I want us back on schedule.
我们确信它坏掉了
We think it's broken.
你们就不能做好一件事吗?
Can't you do anything right?
像伯纳黛特这样的修道院好女孩
So, how did a good convent girl like Bernadette
怎么会出现在这个德·威赫船长的船舱里呢?
come to be in the cabin of this Captain De Vere?
为何他想把她从联邦酒店中诱拐出来呢?
And why did he try to abduct her from the Federal Hotel?
如果真是他的话
If it was him.
但并没有一辆登记在德·威赫名下的
There's no car...big, black or otherwise
黑色大轿车或者其他车
registered in the name of De Vere.
因为他是比利时人 那车一定是他同谋所有
Well, he's Belgian. Must belong to an accomplice.
- 车什么型号 - 凯迪拉克
- What kind of car was it? - A Cadillac.
通常 我会把这案子交给乔治处理
Under normal circumstances, I'd take this to George.
就是桑德森专员
Well, Commissioner Sanderson.
但你现在自身难保 工作都快丢了
But you're already perilously close to being out of a job.
你不觉得现在别跟他对着干才是明智之举吗
You don't think it's wise to antagonise him any further?
你警察的身份对我的帮助大得多了 杰克
You're much more use to me if you remain a policeman, Jack.
但我这个警察没法把任何人带进局子问询
A policeman who can't bring anyone into the station for questioning.
我无意冒犯 但在我的会客厅问询更舒适
No offence, but my parlour is much more comfortable.
为什么一个修道院女孩会出现
Why would a Gratitude girl be in
在一个比利时船长的船舱里?
the cabin of a Belgian sea captain?
我们现在只能猜测
We can only speculate at the moment.
她会是偷渡客吗?
You think she was a stowaway?
有可能是
That's one possible explanation, yes.
她要出去看看花花世界呗
Oh. Off to see the world.
但那并不能解释伯纳黛特在忏悔室的墙上
But that doesn't explain why Bernadette carved the Captain's name
刻下船长名字的原因
into the Penitence Room wall.
也不能解释她手腕上绳子的绑痕
Or why her hands were bound.
可能因为...她是在拘留室被人发现的
Perhaps she was... discovered in the hold.
伯纳黛特有对修女们说过船的事情吗
Did Bernadette say anything to the nuns about a ship?
她知道船长的名字
Well, she knew the name of the captain.
所以他们一定有交集 还有别的信息吗?
So their paths must have crossed. Any more than that?
只知道这么多
We don't know.
不管伯纳黛特身上发生了什么事 我们要想想
Whatever happened to Bernadette, we... we need to consider...
乔安会不会也是这么不见的
..Joan may have gone the same way.
你觉得她们是一起逃走的?
You think they ran away together?
可能我对乔安说话有点太严厉了
Perhaps I was a little too snappy with Joan.
但她需要学习啊
But she needed to learn.
还有其他的女孩
Do you know if any other girls went missing
从修道院逃走吗?
from their Gratitude placements?
杰克 你不觉得你应该
Jack, don't you think you should
把这些线索都告诉爸爸吗?
pass all this information on to Father?
你觉得那样好吗?
Do you think that's wise?
他都不让杰克参与这个案子
Considering he took Jack off the case?
他别无选择 主教死死盯着他呢
He didn't have a choice, the Bishop was breathing down his neck.
你在这边横加干涉 一点忙也帮不上
And your constant meddling hasn't helped.
亲爱的 杰克是对的
Darling, Jack's right.
乔治是新的行政专员
As the new chief commissioner,
比起杰克 他受到的限制更大
George's hands are even more tightly bound than Jack's.
我给你修道院劳务人员的名单
I'll get you a list of the Gratitude employers.
通讯簿在我车里
My address book's out in the car.
太好了 我会把它转交给 柯林斯
Good. I'll get them on to Collins.
你让杰克的处境变得更糟糕了 知道吗?
You've really made things worse for Jack, you know?
作为一个前妻 这关心的是不是有点过分呢
Unusually devoted, isn't she? For an ex-wife.
潘达斯号本应在下周起航
Pandarus was due to sail next week.
但是它将要在今夜出发
But it turns out she's sailing tonight.
航海日程表突然变更了
Sudden change in itinerary.
这很可疑 它现在应该已经起航了
Well, that's suspicious. She could've sailed already.
不 海风很大
Nah. She won't want
它不会在海面平静下来之前出发的
to go through the heads until slack water.
也就是今夜子时左右
Tonight around midnight.
我要通知桑德森专员 他现在应该采取行动了
I'll inform the Commissioner. He'll have to act now.
你可以等桑德森采取行动 但我不会静观其变
You can wait for Sanderson to act, but I'm not holding my breath.
等等 等等
No, wait, wait.
不管他是做绑架还是谋杀的生意
Whether he's trading in kidnap or murder,
那个船长就是个人渣
that captain's a nasty piece of work.
我不想让任何人靠近码头
I don't want anyone to go near the docks.
拜托了 费雪小姐
Please, Miss Fisher.
就这一次 你一定要听我的
Do what you're told just this once.
我会...告诉你我发现了什么
I'll... let you know what I find.
杰克探长说得对 这会比我想的要危险得多
The Inspector's right. It's far more dangerous than I imagined.
但是我全副武装 而且枪法精准
But I am well armed and an excellent shot.
我们不能这样做 小姐?
We can't do anything, Miss?
泡壶热茶等着我就最好不过了
A thermos of tea would be lovely.
你怎么想呢 西西?
What do you reckon, Cec?
我们要"铁拳出击"吗?
Fists of steel?
这很冒险
Could be risky.
先生们 如果你们担心武器问题的话
If weaponry is your only problem, gentlemen,
我能帮上忙
I may be able to assist.
这是毛瑟C96半自动手枪
And this is the Mauser Broomhandle semi-automatic.
当然跟那把Mp18没法比 但也够用了
Not quite as impressive as the MP18, but so much more competent.
这些够用了
These should do the job.
- 多谢 B先生 - 乐意效劳
- Thanks, Mr B. - Happy to help.
你说这个已经上交了不是吗
You said that was handed in.
这是在潘达斯号停靠的码头发现的
Found at the docks, near the Pandarus.
有这个足以申请突袭搜查令了
Well, that is certainly enough for a raid warrant.
太好了 它就快起航了
Good. We've only got
我们只有几个小时的时间
a few hours before she sails.
如果你给我搜查令和一些人手
If you organise the paperwork and the manpower,
我跟柯林斯现在就赶往码头
Collins and I can head to the docks.
抱歉 杰克 我很感谢你的帮助
I'm afraid not, Jack. Look, I appreciate your help.
但是这案子不归你管
But this is not your investigation
而且你现在已经越权了
and you've already overstepped the mark.
欧·谢贺尼斯就是个蠢货!
O'Shaughnessy's an imbecile!
如果船起航了 杀人凶手就被你放走了
If that ship sails, you'll be letting a murderer get away.
我明白欧·谢贺尼斯的无能 杰克
I'm aware of O'Shaughnessy's limitations, Jack.
所以我要亲自带队抓捕
That's why I'll be leading this raid myself.
但我现在命令你别碍事儿
But I'm ordering you to stop interfering.
如果你不服从的话...
If you disobey...
我会毫不犹豫把你开掉
I won't hesitate to dismiss you.
医生说现在去分娩室已经太迟了
The doctor says it's too late to go to the lying-in home.
他很快就会赶来
He'll get here as soon as he can.
不 我不需要医生 现在还不是时候!
No! I don't need a doctor! It's not my time!
抓紧我
Hold on to me.
哦 亲爱的
Oh, dear.
我现在就去烧水 给剪刀消毒
I'll boil up some water and get the scissors sterilised.
拿一些毛巾过来 巴特勒先生 需要很多毛巾
And bring some towels, Mr Butler. Loads of towels.
不不不 什么也别拿过来!
No, no, no! Don't bring anything!
现在还不是时候!
It's not my time!
别胡说 姑娘
Nonsense, girl.
保佑我吧 神父 我是个有罪之人
Bless me, Father, for I have sinned.
我以前做过坏事
I've been bad and wicked
上帝会让那些修女拿走我的宝宝的!
and God is going to let the nuns take my baby away!
上帝不会做这种事的 不然我早就遭报应了
God will do nothing of the kind or he'll be answerable to me!
现在给我振作起来 姑娘 你有大事要做呢
Now pull yourself together, girl, you've got work to do.
"分娩"还有个意思叫"劳动"
It's not called 'labour'
不是毫无缘由的
for nothing.
没看到黑色的车
No sign of the black car.
- 甲板上也没人 - 岸边看上去没有危险
- No one on deck either. - Looks like the coast is clear.
低下你的头 关上车门 多蒂
Keep your head down and the doors locked, Dot.
你知道老鼠和沉船的谚语吗[船沉鼠先逃]
You know what they say about rats and sinking ships.
也许德·威赫接到了警告
Maybe De Vere's been warned.
如果真是这样
If he had been,
那潘达斯号这会已经在半路上了
the Pandarus would be halfway up to sea by now.
如果他们在船上藏着什么人的话
Well, if there are holding anybody on board,
很难发现他们
it'll be hard to find 'em.
走私犯都狡猾的很
Smugglers are a crafty lot.
要不然我们怎么能弄到你的法国香槟
How do you think we get your French champagne into the country?
还有你钟爱的俄国鱼子酱?
Or that Russian caviar you're so partial to.
我以为你是从维多利亚市场买来的 波特
Here I was thinking you picked it up from Victoria Markets, Bert.
谁在那儿?
Who's there?
乔安
Joan!
费雪小姐 是你吗? 我看不清
Miss Fisher, is that you? I can't see.
乔安 没事了
Joan, it's alright.
求你了 快带我走 求你了 他就快回来了
Please, we have to leave. Please, he'll come back.
- 嘘 - 求你了
- Sh! Please!
你现在很安全 你很安全
You're safe now. You're safe now.
乔安
Joan.
坐这儿
Here.
喝了这茶 能暖和点
This tea should keep you warm.
给你
Here.
费雪小姐怎么还没出来?
What the hell's happened to Miss Fisher?
我希望她能在他回来之前找到其他人
I hope she finds the others before it's too late.
其他人?
What others?
在来船上之前 他们把我跟其他人关在一起
I was locked up with the others before they brought us water.
然后我就逃走了
That's when I escaped.
我们得回去
Come on, we're going back.
给我下车! 快点!
Get out of car! Come here!
快点! 出来!
Come here! Get out!
哦 小可怜们
Oh, you poor lambs.
我想我得把你绑起来了
I'm afraid I'll have to tie you up.
但我觉得 你一定更喜欢被关在单独的房间吧
But I'm sure you'd prefer your own cabin anyway.
下来
Come down.
快!
Now!
柯林斯
Collins.
- 有突袭的消息了吗? - 没有 先生
- Any news on the raid? - No, sir.
不过我追踪那辆黑色轿车
But I managed to track down
发现了一些线索
some more details on that black motor car.
那辆车登记在一个公司名下
It's registered to a company, sir.
叫Swf出口公司
An SWF Exports.
Swf 好耳熟 公司属谁所有?
SWF. Sounds familiar. Who owns it?
你在这干嘛 杰克?
What are you doing here, Jack?
我告诉过你 一切都在掌控之中
I told you everything was under control.
恐怕不是这样 你的人手呢
Doesn't look like it. Where's your manpower?
我会以我觉得合适的方法来处理
I will handle this any way I see fit.
你俩要是踏上那艘船 就别想在警局混了
You two set one foot on that ship, your jobs are finished.
你可以走 柯林斯
You can go, Collins.
不 谢谢先生 我不走
No, thank you, sir.
你可以谴责我
You can reprimand me.
你也可以解雇我 但我就是要搜船
You can dismiss me if you like. But I am searching that ship.
她在哪儿
Where is she?
我说了别登上这艘船 杰克
I told you not to set foot on this ship, Jack.
乔治 你到底在隐瞒什么?
George, what the hell are you covering up?
我警告过你 杰克
I warned you, Jack!
警察 把他铐起来 把他铐在这根柱子上
Constable, handcuff him! Constable, handcuff him to this post!
然后把他留在这儿
And leave him there.
费雪小姐!
Miss Fisher!
芬乐妮? 费雪小姐!
Phryne? Miss Fisher!
费雪小姐!
Miss Fisher!
你在哪里
Where are you?
- 费雪小姐! - 杰克!
- Miss Fisher? - Jack!
杰克!
Jack!
- 费雪小姐! - 杰克!
- Miss Fisher? - Jack!
杰克 那些女孩被关在在前面的拘留室
Jack, the girls are locked in the front hold
这一切都是弗莱彻搞的鬼
and Fletcher's behind it all!
我们得在弗莱彻动手之前救出她们
We've got to get the girls before Fletcher does.
多蒂
Dottie!
弗莱彻!
Fletcher!
站住 站住
Stop! Stop!
我们要他钓出来吗 先生?
Shall we fish him out, sir?
势在必行啊
I suppose we'll have to.
不着急 慢慢来
Make sure you take your time.
多蒂 波特 西西 干得不错
Dot, Bert, Cec, well done.
铁拳出击 小姐 铁拳出击
Fists of steel, Miss. Fists of steel.
你不让我发誓言
You wouldn't let me take my vows,
所以我尽我所能帮教堂
so I was serving the church however I could.
以送走这些女孩的方式?
By sending those girls away?
德·威赫付我十磅一人
£10 a piece De Vere paid me.
每一分钱我都捐出来做善事了 修女
And every penny of it went into the good works fund, Mother.
- 我发誓 - 一人十磅
- I swear it. - £10 a piece.
弗莱彻确保选中的
And Fletcher made sure
女孩都是白人 一袭秀发 善良贞洁
all the chosen girls were white, fair-haired and virtuous.
因此交易得名为"白金买卖"
What's known in the trade as White Gold.
你利用无辜女孩实现自己目的
You used innocent girls to further your own cause.
无辜?
Innocent?
她们都是私生女 大多数都是妓女的孩子
They were born out of wedlock, most of them, the offspring of whores.
她们的灵魂已经堕落
Their souls were already lost.
是你的灵魂堕落了 波普塔
It's your soul that's lost, Perpetua.
我把它落在车里了
I lost them at the back of that car.
伯纳黛特发现了
And Bernadette found them
德·威赫也想那样掳走她
when De Vere tried to abduct her the same way.
你的眼镜给了伯纳黛特警告
Your spectacles were Bernadette's warning...
让她逃
..to flee.
她留给我的吗
She left them for me?
还留下了找到你们全部人的线索
Along with the clue we needed to find you all.
他们为什么要杀她
Why did they kill her?
她已经逃出一次了 她知道的太多了
She'd already escaped once, and she knew too much.
船长是遵弗莱彻之命
The captain was carrying out Fletcher's orders.
我愿他下地狱
I hope he burns in hell!
弗莱彻在讨价还价
Fletcher's bargaining power.
有名望顾客的纪念品 城里最好的妓院
All souvenirs from the best clients, the best brothels in town.
盒子里可没有我的东西
There is nothing of mine in that box.
我想关掉妓院 他又不能勒索我
I tried to close down the brothels. He couldn't blackmail me.
但他可以贿赂你
But he could bribe you.
承诺扳倒专员豪尔
By promising to bring down Commissioner Hall with all this,
你可以取而代之
so you could take his place.
你得先证明这一切
You'll have to prove it first.
是的 幸运的是 我们有目击者
True. And luckily, we have a witness.
我阿姨感恩晚餐那晚
The night of my aunt's Gratitude dinner,
她的厨房女仆 乔安 碰巧听见你和
her scullery maid, Joan, overheard you and Fletcher
弗莱彻在阳台激烈讨论
having a heated discussion on the verandah.
我们知道你帮了他的忙 保护弗莱彻
We know you did him favours, protected Fletcher,
对他贩卖人口睁一只眼闭一只眼
turned a blind eye to his... cargo.
乔安本不该在那艘船上的是吗
Joan wasn't meant to be on that ship, was she?
她被掳走是因为听到太多
She was abducted because she'd heard too much.
谁会在意流浪孩的话
Who's going to believe the word of a guttersnipe?
再别提是针对行政专员的流言
Against that of the chief commissioner of police.
我阿姨普顿斯·斯坦利 碰巧很爱乔安
My aunt, Prudence Stanley, happens to be very fond of Joan.
她会带以最高的推荐信
So she will come with the highest references,
并配备最贵的律师代表团
and have the best legal representation that money can buy.
我崇敬过你 乔治
I looked up to you, George.
我尊敬过你
I respected you.
我不知道弗莱彻想要干嘛 萝丝 我发誓
I didn't know what Fletcher was up to, Rosie. I swear.
你怎么可能不知道?
How could you not know?
那些可怜的姑娘
Those poor girls!
- 求你了 求你理解我 - 你怎么能?
- Please, please try to understand. - How could you?
你怎么能这样 我无法直视你
How could you? I can't look at you.
天啊
Oh, God!
- 我很抱歉 - 别...
- (I'm sorry.) - Oh, don't...
杰克...
Oh, Jack...
不 天啊
Oh, no. Oh, God...
- 他们都这么红吗? - 当然
- Are they always this red? - Always.
可医生说这位跟小牛一样壮
But the doctor says this one is as strong as an ox.
对不对呀 小玩意
Aren't you, my little man?
太棒了
Wonderful.
现在我们要做的就是为玛丽找处落脚
Now all we need to do is find a placement for Mary.
她在我这落脚啊
She already has a placement with me.
当然 她康复了就能走
Once she's completely recovered, of course.
- 她能干吗 - 她能帮厨啊
- Doing what? - She can assist Cook.
我坚信假以时日 她做的汤
I've no doubt that her soup will come up to scratch
一定会有味道的
once she's had a bit of practice.
- 她的蛋奶甜点心呢? - 其实挺不错的
- And her flummery? - Quite good, actually.
没事的 斯坦利太太 我能接手
It's alright, Mrs Stanley. I can take over.
- 很好 谢谢你 多蒂 - 再见
- Good. Thank you, Dot. - Bye-bye.
我脑子里都是别人杀人放火 违法犯纪的事
How am I going to be able to come home to you and our own kids...
怎么回家面对你和孩子们呢?
..when my head's so full of these terrible things people do?
那女孩跟你差不了多少 多蒂
That girl wasn't much younger than you, Dottie.
要是你没遇到费雪小姐
If you hadn't had met Miss Fisher,
可能就发生在你身上了
that could've been you.
可我遇见费雪小姐了 那不是我
But I did meet Miss Fisher, and it wasn't me.
世界上还是有好事的
And there are good things in the world too.
看啊
Look.
- 我以为你和萝丝在一起 - 刚刚是
- I thought you were with Rosie. - I was.
- 太晚了吗 - 从不会
- Is it too late? - Never.
我从没见过她那样
I've never seen her like that before.
她惊呆了 她需要人陪
She was in shock. She... just needed some company.
她需要你 杰克·罗宾森
She needed you, Jack Robinson.
一位正直不阿的男人
The man who always does the right thing.
做光荣的事
The noble thing.
- 也不总是 费雪小姐 - 那是婴儿吗
- Not always, Miss Fisher. - Was that the baby?
- 天这么晚了 探长 - 是的 的确
- Oh. It's very late, Inspector. - Yes. Yes, it is.
但我很高兴我们说清了 费雪小姐
But I'm glad we cleared up that detail, Miss Fisher.
我也是 杰克 我也很高兴
So am I, Jack. So am I.
好了 小家伙 我来了
It's alright, little man. I'm coming.
那下个谋杀案见了
Until our next murder investigation, then.
我很期待
I look forward to it.
期待破案啦 不是期待谋杀
The investigation, not... not the murder.
当然
Of course.
再见杰克
Jack.
再见费雪小姐
Miss Fisher.